<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-02T02:28:18-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Analysis of the Democratic Presidential Debates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/politics/2019/07/02/analysis-of-debates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Analysis of the Democratic Presidential Debates" /><published>2019-07-02T01:21:04-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-02T01:21:04-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/politics/2019/07/02/analysis-of-debates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/politics/2019/07/02/analysis-of-debates.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m putting so much research into this shit :’( Bear with me it’s gonna take a little
while before it comes out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’m putting so much research into this shit :’( Bear with me it’s gonna take a little while before it comes out.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Commercialization of Pride Month</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/politics/2019/07/02/commercialization-of-pride.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Commercialization of Pride Month" /><published>2019-07-02T01:21:04-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-02T01:21:04-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/politics/2019/07/02/commercialization-of-pride</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/politics/2019/07/02/commercialization-of-pride.html">&lt;p&gt;Okay so I don’t yet have this post written but I’m going to talk about why I don’t
personally go to the pride parade and how necessary for companies and public figures
pride has become. There’s a number of memes about this (mostly referring to how as soon
as July hits it’s back to what essentially boils down to straight pride and forgetting
the reason pride is necessary anyway). This year, being the 50th anniversary of the
Stonewall Riots, there’s been a particularly big push. A number of articles was written
about how Taylor Swift’s song, which compares the peril that many members of the LGBT+
community face to her own struggles of being famous, as tone-deaf at best.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Okay so I don’t yet have this post written but I’m going to talk about why I don’t personally go to the pride parade and how necessary for companies and public figures pride has become. There’s a number of memes about this (mostly referring to how as soon as July hits it’s back to what essentially boils down to straight pride and forgetting the reason pride is necessary anyway). This year, being the 50th anniversary of the Stonewall Riots, there’s been a particularly big push. A number of articles was written about how Taylor Swift’s song, which compares the peril that many members of the LGBT+ community face to her own struggles of being famous, as tone-deaf at best.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Critical Thinking</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/philosophy/2019/07/02/critical-thinking.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Critical Thinking" /><published>2019-07-02T01:21:04-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-02T01:21:04-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/philosophy/2019/07/02/critical-thinking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/philosophy/2019/07/02/critical-thinking.html">&lt;p&gt;This piece is definitely going to be a difficult one to write. I’m a big fan of
this philosophy/literary blog called “Brain Pickings”. In this blog, the author
has already touched on critical thinking far better than I could ever hope to.
She speaks about Descarte’s 12 Rules of Critical Thinking not to mention the views
of Buddha, Galileo, Carl Sagan and so many others. Instead, I’m going to explore
the idea of critical thinking about how it relates to the way intelligent people
can fall for false news.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This piece is definitely going to be a difficult one to write. I’m a big fan of this philosophy/literary blog called “Brain Pickings”. In this blog, the author has already touched on critical thinking far better than I could ever hope to. She speaks about Descarte’s 12 Rules of Critical Thinking not to mention the views of Buddha, Galileo, Carl Sagan and so many others. Instead, I’m going to explore the idea of critical thinking about how it relates to the way intelligent people can fall for false news.</summary></entry></feed>