<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Some of my thoughts in blog form</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Critical Thinking</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This piece is definitely going to be a difficult one to write. I’m a big fan of
this philosophy/literary blog called “Brain Pickings”. In this blog, the author
has already touched on critical thinking far better than I could ever hope to.
She speaks about Descarte’s 12 Rules of Critical Thinking not to mention the views
of Buddha, Galileo, Carl Sagan and so many others. Instead, I’m going to explore
the idea of critical thinking about how it relates to the way intelligent people
can fall for false news.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 01:21:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//philosophy/2019/07/02/critical-thinking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//philosophy/2019/07/02/critical-thinking.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Commercialization of Pride Month</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay so I don’t yet have this post written but I’m going to talk about why I don’t
personally go to the pride parade and how necessary for companies and public figures
pride has become. There’s a number of memes about this (mostly referring to how as soon
as July hits it’s back to what essentially boils down to straight pride and forgetting
the reason pride is necessary anyway). This year, being the 50th anniversary of the
Stonewall Riots, there’s been a particularly big push. A number of articles was written
about how Taylor Swift’s song, which compares the peril that many members of the LGBT+
community face to her own struggles of being famous, as tone-deaf at best.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 01:21:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//politics/2019/07/02/commercialization-of-pride.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//politics/2019/07/02/commercialization-of-pride.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Analysis of the Democratic Presidential Debates</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m putting so much research into this shit :’( Bear with me it’s gonna take a little
while before it comes out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 01:21:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//politics/2019/07/02/analysis-of-debates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//politics/2019/07/02/analysis-of-debates.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Mailing List!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not 100% sure what my email mailing list really looks like yet so this is
sort of an update to make sure it all works? I’ve got a little subscribe
pop up that shows up on my website as well as an embedded permanent subscription
thing. Theoretically an email will be sent every morning at 8AM after I post
which I’m hoping is about once a week?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 01:21:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//update/2019/07/02/Mailing-List.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//update/2019/07/02/Mailing-List.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
